<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tutorial on Cameron&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>/tags/tutorial/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tutorial on Cameron&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2018 03:11:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/tutorial/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>My GEFCom2017 paper</title>
      <link>/post/2018-09-28-gefcom2017-tut/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2018 03:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-09-28-gefcom2017-tut/</guid>
      <description>Caveat Emptor!: This is a work in progress! I’m refactoring the original code I wrote. Trying to find a nice balance between wrapping functions up in the gefcom2017 package and using existing R packages such as purrr. This post has been uploaded early so I can include a link in the paper.
Introduction This post shows how to implement the model I propose in the paper “Reconciled boosted models for GEFCom2017 hierarchical probabilistic load forecasting”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 minute tidyverse: readr</title>
      <link>/post/2017-10-17-tidyverse-readr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2017 14:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2017-10-17-tidyverse-readr/</guid>
      <description>Despite appearing fairly innocuous, loading data can be one of the most frustrating challenges when starting a data science project. Missing values, trailing commas, renegade quotes in strings and many other issues can all cause headaches when reading a csv file. I’m sure many an aspiring data scientist has been left feeling discouraged after falling at this early hurdle - I know I have.
This post introduces some basics of loading data using a csv.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 minute tidyverse</title>
      <link>/post/2017-11-25-tidyverse/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2017 10:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2017-11-25-tidyverse/</guid>
      <description>This series of blog posts gives a brief introduction to R’s tidyverse. The tidyverse is a fantastic framework for shaping, exploring and visualising data. Consistent syntax, intuitive behaviour and excellent performance are the main reasons to learn this set of tools. Furthermore, tidyverse packages have stickers that may be assembled into a geometrically pleasing hex formation.
 Figure 1: I’ll never stop.  Structure Each of the key tidyverse packages will be introduced in a separate post.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>